<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Edinburghs joy for His Majesties coronation in England.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1661</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 16 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 6 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A82962</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing E173</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R223306</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">45789277</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 45789277</idno>
            <idno type="VID">172590</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A82962)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 172590)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2640:6)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Edinburghs joy for His Majesties coronation in England.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>8 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[Edinburgh :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Printed in the year, 1661.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Place of publication suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Date of publication from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: print show-through with some loss of print.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the University of Illinois (Urbana-Champaign Campus). Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Charles --  II, --  King of England, 1630-1685.</term>
               <term>Scotland --  History --  1660-1688.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-10</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-10</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:172590:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 73 -->
            <head>EDINBURGHS JOY FOR HIS MAJESTIES Coronation in ENGLAND.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">R</seg>Oom there, Give way a little to <hi>Edinen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſis,</hi> What? Why? is not whiffling <hi>Caledonius</hi> gone; certainly he hath been only Babbon-ſtruck, or Prieſt-ſtab'd, I need not fear he will peep out again; his muzzel'd mouth and hapſhakled pen dar neither mute nor give a daſh againſt ſo potent an <hi>&amp;c.</hi> elſe ſurely the Wag had been diſcovering the Affairs of our <hi>Scots</hi> World, (for further I believe he durſt not) what his Parliament which he magnified ſo much (and yet deſervedly) had been acting this three weeks bygone; and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deed
<pb n="1" facs="tcp:172590:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 74 -->
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:172590:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 75 -->it could have been well wiſhed that that unparalelled act which cut off root and branch, every thing which either might kindle or give life to Rebellion had been timeouſly made known, that all Fanaticks whatſoever might know what they have to truſt to from us, and ſo bid farewell, (or father fare-ill) to all the traſh and trumpery hanging on and annexed to both the Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venants.</p>
            <p>But what then? muſt <hi>Caledonia</hi> ſuffer, becauſe of <hi>Caledonius</hi> overſhooting himſelf, let him go ſearch, and beſtow his Stock to purchaſe Forraigne Intelligence from <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>topia</hi> if he will, yet we ought to know our ſelves; That Smatterer in Latine would have called this (<gap reason="foreign">
                  <desc>〈 in non-Latin alphabet 〉</desc>
               </gap>) eſpecially what <hi>Edina</hi> the Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tropolis is doing to expreſſe her Joy in behalf of her Dread So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veraignes glorious Coronation in <hi>England;</hi> April 23. 1661. On which day ſet apart for Thankſgiving, the Lord High <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioner</hi> accompanied with the Officers of State, and His MA<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>JESTIES Life-guard in rich Furniture and ſumptuous Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parell, under the Command of Mr. <hi>Murray</hi> Brother to the Earl of <hi>Athole,</hi> went from the Palace of <hi>Holy rude-houſe</hi> to the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment Houſe, where they heard Sermon Preached by that reverend Divine D. <hi>James Sharpe,</hi> quite of another ſtrain then that at <hi>Scoone,</hi> Anno 1651. Heer our late proceedings were repented, and not juſtified: (but leſt it befall me as it did to <hi>Caledonius</hi>) I pray in that Sermon view pag. 10. <hi>A King abuſing his Power,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>pag.</hi> 17. and <hi>pag.</hi> 4. there are many ſins, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> (:) to the great honour of the Preacher, and ſatisfaction of the Auditory. It was no leſſe cheerfully and cordially done through the other Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gregations of the City, and bleſſed be God for it among other glorious recoveries, Prieſt and People are reſtored to their wits.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Sermon</hi> ended, the Lord <hi>Commiſſioner</hi> returned to the Royal Palace attended by great numbers of Nobility, Knights and Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, and all Feaſted at one time, and at ſeveral Tables in a moſt ſplendid and magnificent manner: And that nothing might be wanting to compleat the Solemnity, the Lord <hi>Commiſſioners</hi> Lady with her Daughters at the ſame time in another Room en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tertained
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:172590:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 75 -->many Ladies of quality with all the rarities and deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cacies imaginable, and with ſuch admirable Conſorts of Muſick as hardly could been expected from a Nation ſo depreſſed: To<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards the middle of Dinner, His MAJESTIES Health be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gun by the Lord <hi>Commiſſioner,</hi> a ſigne given from the Tarras, the Canons of the Caſtle begun to thunder, which was anſwered from the Cittadell of <hi>Leith</hi> with the like roaring; and the great pyramide of Coals and Tar-Barrels which was in the out Court of the Palace was likewiſe given fire to, which for its greatneſſe was extraordinary, and if it had been on the top of a hill in the night time, for two miles about it would ſhowen light to have ſung <hi>Te Deums</hi> in the ſmalleſt Print, and put into a ſweat any that had been frozen with the greateſt fit of a cold, and at the ſame diſtance too. After Dinner, the young Lords and Ladies came out and Danced all ſort of Comtrey Dances and Reels, and none buſier then the young Lord <hi>Cleremont</hi> Son to the Lord <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioner</hi> who was ſo raviſhed with joy, that if he had not been reſtrained he had thrown Rings, Chains, Jewels and all that was precious about him into the Fire.</p>
            <p>Now let us take a little notice of the great ſigns of Joy mani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſted by our Ancient and good Town of <hi>Edinburgh:</hi> After the Lord proveſt Sir <hi>Robert Murray,</hi> with the Bailies, Common Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſel and other Magiſtrates had turned up their Spiritual Thanks to Heaven for ſo bleſſed an occaſion, then they went altogether to a place appointed for the purpoſe, and in a moſt magnificent manner, regalled themſelves with thoſe humane lawfull Refreſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, which is allowable for the Grandour of ſo Eminent a Bleſſing: By that time their Feaſt was finiſhed, the Bonefire Bells allarmed them to minde the carrying on the Work of the Night: The Lord Proveſt, with the Magiſtrates, each of them with a white Batton in their hands, and the reſt of the Counſel, appeared at the Croſſe, which was diſpoſed in a moſt hoſpitable piece of Pagiantry, <hi>viz.</hi> A ſplendid repreſentation of a Vine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yard, with all the Cognizances of <hi>Bachus,</hi> and under a large Wine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tree of ſwelling and Ruddy Cluſters, did that ſame god of Fro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licks, beſtride a Hogs-head of the moſt gracious Claret: he was
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:172590:4"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 76 -->accompanied with his Uncle <hi>Silenus,</hi> and ſome half a ſcore of moſt lovely and wanton <hi>Bachides:</hi> this ſame Grave and Spungy Moderator, by Proclamation, gave moſt ample permiſſion to all mankind, for the ſpace of twelve hours by the clock, to be as madd with mirth as their imaginations could fancy: The Indul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gence was no ſooner pronounced, but Streams of Claret guſhed from the Conduits: Trumpets, Fluts, and all ſort of Carrouſing Inſtruments which might skrue up the paſſions, did forthwith ſound a Charge: the breaking of Glaſſes, and tumbling of Gob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lets amongſt the Commonality, made a greater noiſe then the claſhing of <hi>Zrexes</hi> Armies Armour did at a narrow Paſſe, when they were upon a Rout. But indeed, the Magiſtrates with a moſt becoming gravity, and extraordinary chearfulneſſe, did round the Healths of His MAJESTIE, and Royal Relations. By this time all the private Bonefires was at their height: then as the Lord Proveſt had formerly appointed, there was five hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Musketiers of the Train-bands, commanded by <hi>John Fuller<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>toun</hi> Captain of the firſt Regiment and his reſpective Officers that were not upon Duty, <hi>viz.</hi> Captain <hi>John Dunbar,</hi> Captain <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert Baird,</hi> Captain <hi>Thomas Wilſon,</hi> Captain <hi>William Hamiltoun,</hi> Captain <hi>Thomas Crawford,</hi> Captain <hi>Thomas Brand,</hi> Captain <hi>John Johnſtoun,</hi> all theſe Worthy Perſons being of approven Loyalty, Diſcretion and Courage did in a ſtragling way, deſcend ſo far as to officiat as Serjeants, to keep the crowd from the Lord Proveſt and Magiſtrates, as he march'd along to the Palace Royal, the above mentioned Musketiers in gallant order marching before the Magiſtrates and Common Counſel. In the Rear of whom, there were four hundred Citizens with Partizans, led by Captain <hi>John Meen,</hi> firſt captain of the ſecond Regiment, and the ſeverall Captains thereto belonging, <hi>viz.</hi> Captain <hi>James Scot,</hi> Captain <hi>James Curry,</hi> Captain <hi>David Boyd,</hi> Captain <hi>Alexander Pearſon,</hi> Captain <hi>Edward Cleghorn,</hi> Captain <hi>Robert Gray,</hi> Captain <hi>George Trumble,</hi> all of them of equal qualifications with the others: The Worthy Perſon who commanded this Squadron of Partizans, <hi>viz.</hi> Captain <hi>John Meen,</hi> becauſe there be others of the ſame name in Town, it is fitting he be diſtinguiſhed; for this is he who
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:172590:4"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 76 -->hath loſt three ſeveral Stocks in providing His MAJESTIES Forces with Armes, and that he be not miſtaken to be one of theſe who ſerved His MAJESTIE the wrong way, take notice that his firſt was in providing the Marqueſſe of <hi>Montroſſe,</hi> which was ſo conſiderable, as would have overſet any ordinary ſpirit: The ſecond was with the ſame ſucceſſe when Duke <hi>Hamiltoun</hi> enter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priſed His MAJESTIES relief, in <hi>Anno</hi> 1648. A third which was greateſt of all, was immediately before His MAJE<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>STIES going to <hi>Worſter,</hi> where he had a Ship loadened with Ammunition for the uſe of the Country made Prize by the Uſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pers: Yet notwithſtanding all theſe loſſes and miſchiefs which ſuc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeded one another, God Almighty is pleaſed to proſper his un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dertakings, and particularly in the diligent diſcharge of his truſt, when he was Theſaurer to <hi>Heriots</hi> Hoſpital, where he was moſt in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrumental in procuring the removal of all theſe obſtructions, which did vitiate the Will of the Foundator, ſo that now it may be properly tearmed an Hoſpital. But that which hath rendered him moſt famous, was his kindneſſe to His MAJESTIES priſoners; for beſides<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> relieving many Gentlemens ſons from the <hi>Barbadoes,</hi> he never ſcrupled to engage perſon and fortune for any that were by the Uſurpers ſecured upon jealouſies, and all theſe courteſies he purchaſed without either being ſhaken, or diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſembling his Royal Principles. Thus much we have made known of this honeſt Subject and Noble Good-fellow, that others here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after may be encouraged to do handſome actions, ſo at leſt they can never want the merit of fame and admiration.</p>
            <p>But let us return to the Lord Proveſt, who with this Guard of Musketiers and Partizans, came to the Lord <hi>Commiſſtoners</hi> Bonefire, where he was entertained by many Noblemen and Ladies, and at the rounding of the Royal Health, our Fire-men acquit themſelves with admirable Vollies of Shot: In fine, there could be nothing more expreſſed of an Univerſal and Superlative Joy. And as the Lord Proveſt returned to the Town, he was regalled at the Bonefires of ſeveral perſons of quality, and for a time, gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vity was laid aſide to give place to all ſort of Frisking and Gam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boling, and nothing was more out of faſhion and ridiculous, then
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:172590:5"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 77 -->to ſee any one man in the ſpace of three minuts, not to be hang<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing two of them in the Aire with Capriols. But amongſt all our Bontadoes and Caprices, that of the immortal <hi>Jenet Geddis,</hi> Princeſſe-of the <hi>Trone</hi> Adventurers, was moſt pleaſant, for ſhe was not only content to aſſemble all her Creels, Basquets, Creepees, Fums, and the other Ingredients that compoſed the Shope of her Sallets, Radiſhes, Turnips, Carrets, Spinnage, Cabbage, with all other ſort of Pot Merchandiſe that belongs to the Garden; but even her Weather Chair of State where ſhe uſed to diſpenſe Juſtice to the reſt of her Langkale Vaſſals, were all very orderly burned, ſhe her ſelf countenancing the Action with a high flown Claret and Vermilion Majeſty.</p>
            <p>In all this pleaſant madneſſe which was ſtrange, there was not any inconveniency at all happened, and even amongſt the <hi>Canalia,</hi> there was not the leaſt diſorder. And to conclude the dayes. Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bile, we were advertized of joyful tydings from the North, to wit, the Provincial Synod of the Church of <hi>Aberdene,</hi> hath made a ſolemn acknowledgement of all their rebellious Defections, Hy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pocriſies and Oppreſſions, by which they either miſled the people againſt His MAJESTIE, or trampled upon their Brethren who refuſed to commit Idolatry with either of the Dagons, National or League: They have ordained before the beginning of Sermon on the Sundays, that the reading of the Holy Scriptures, and Prayers, be uſed as formerly before the Rebellion, that Glory to the Father ſhall be ſung at the ends of Pſalms, that the Lords Prayer be likewiſe ſaid by the Miniſters, either at their firſt or ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond Prayer: that Parents who preſents their Children to be Chriſtened repeat the Creed, and be oblieged to educate their Children in the Chriſtian Faith, and no more mention to be made of the Articles of the Covenant: They have in Imitation of our State, cancelled all theſe Kirk Acts that might relapſe us in Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bellion. And Petitioners are hourly expected to ſupplicate the Parliament, to have the Government of the Church reſtored. It appeareth, theſe Worthy Divines of the North will as their Laicks been, hath frequent examples of Loyalty, ſo they will be now of Repentance, and the proverb of <hi>Raro vidi Clericum
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:172590:5"/>
                  <!-- PDF PAGE 77 -->paenitentem,</hi> we hope ſhall now periſh, if the reſt of the Brethren be ſo happy as to imitate them. And it is not much to be doubted, for as yet we hear of few Synods but the greateſt part are bluſhing at their bypaſt actions, par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticularly that of <hi>Stirling,</hi> who by the diſcretion of Maſter <hi>Mungo Murray</hi> that ſit with them, have likewiſe exſpunged all theſe Acts that grated upon Loyalty and Obedience. The truth is, moſt of them begins now to ſee that they have been but the ſteps of Great-mens ambition to tread upon, and the weakeſt of them doth likewiſe know when ſuch aſpiring Spirits gains the top of the wall, that they then throw away the Ladder that mounted them, and that now their greateſt ſecurity with the tranquillity of the Kingdom will be, not to diſpute His MAJESTIES Commands, which who ever refuſeth, let him be <hi>Anathema Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinatha.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="notices">
            <head>Advertiſements.</head>
            <p>THe Horſe Race of <hi>Lanerk</hi> Inſtitute by King <hi>William</hi> above 600 years ſince, but obſtructed theſe 23. years by the iniquity of the Times, is now reſtored by Sir <hi>John Wilkie</hi> of <hi>Fouldon,</hi> as being loath ſo Antient a foundation ſhould periſh, and for that effect he hath given <hi>gratis</hi> a piece of Plate of the accuſtomed value, with a ſilver Bell and Sadle to the ſecond and third Horſe; It is to be run the third Tueſday of <hi>May.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Race of <hi>Haddington</hi> is to be run on the 22. of <hi>May</hi> next, the Prize is a moſt magnificent Cup; this ſame Antient Town fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mous for its Hoſpitality, has many times ſadly ſmarted by the Armies of Enemies, yet this glorious Revolution hath ſalved up all their miſeries as very well was made appear by the noble En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tertainment given to the Lord Commiſſioner at the Lord Proveſt <hi>William Seaton</hi> his Lodging, when his Grace made his entry to this Kingdom.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="8" facs="tcp:172590:6"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 78 -->
It was no ſooner noiſed that we was to be <hi>Mercurius</hi> for the Good Town, but we was alarm'd with innumerable <hi>Advertiſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments,</hi> as being oblieged to ſerve every one according to his Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tionall handling; amongſt the reſt, one appeared for <hi>Caledonius,</hi> promiſing a munificent recompence to purchaſe the Copy of a <hi>Latine</hi> Ballad made of him; he could not tell whether it was <hi>in laudem</hi> or <hi>vituperium,</hi> Alas poor <hi>Caledon</hi> thy Enemies though few, thinks thy back at the wall, and ſo would ſmite thee, what may we expect then, a ſhort time of it, for flattery doth not become us, and we dar not tell Truth as thou didſt.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed in the Year, 1661.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
